A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- General Files, 1954
  - Committee--Fellowship Awards (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Final Comprehensive Exams in the College (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Fire Protection (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Foreign Affairs Advisory during Mr. Gange's leave of absence 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Fraternity 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Graduate School of Business (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Honor Professorships (see professorships) (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Honors Courses (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Hospital Architectural Advisory 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Institute for Research in the Social Sciences Council 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Lectures, Special 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Lectures, Page-Barbour and J. W. Richard (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Library (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Lower Division 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--McConnell Award 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--McIntire Undergraduate School of Commerce Advisory 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Mary Washington College 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Mary Washington College President's 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Medical Board of the Hospital 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Mountain Lake Biology Station 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Movie of the University 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Nursing School Advisory 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Parking (see Traffic Control) 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Patents 1955 (Box 10)
  - Committee--Power Plant 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Processions (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Professorships, Special Honor 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Public Occasions 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Research 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Rhodes Scholarship (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Richmond and University Virginia School (see Advanced Standing for Gifted Students) (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Richmond Area University Center Research Council 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Rules and Courses (College) (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Rules and Courses (Medical) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Rushton Seminars 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Schedule and Classroom Assignments (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Scholarships, Loans, and Employment 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Science 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Science Education 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Student Union 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Summer Session (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Summer Session Degrees (college) (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Summer Session Degrees (Graduate) (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Teacher Placement (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Traffic Control 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Tree 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Virginia Quarterly Review (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Committee--Virginia Status of University Students 1955 (Box 11)
  - Comptroller (State) (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1955 (Box 11)
  - Council of State Government (folder empty) 1955 (Box 11)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 11)
  - Davis, W. H. 1955 (Box 11)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 11)
  - Economics 1955 (Box 11)
  - Education 1955 (Box 12)
  - Endowment--Alumni Board of Trustees 1955 (Box 12)
  - Endowment--Contingent Fund 1955 (Box 12)
  - English 1955 (Box 12)
  - Engineering 1955 (Box 12)
  - Enrollment 1955 (Box 12)
  - Extension Division (2 folders) 1955 (Box 13)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 13)
  - Faculty 1955 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Bayly-Tiffany (folder empty) 1955 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Ford Foundation 1955 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Fulbright 1955 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Rhodes 1955 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Thomas Jefferson (folder empty) 1955 (Box 14)
  - Finals 1955 (Box 14)
  - Food Services 1955 (Box 14)
  - Foreign Affairs 1955 (Box 14)
  - Foreign Student Advisor 1955 (Box 14)
  - Forestry 1955 (Box 14)
  - Forms (folder empty) 1955 (Box 14)
  - Founder's Day 1955 (Box 14)
  - Fraternities 1955 (Box 14)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 15)
  - Garden Club 1955 (Box 15)
  - General Education Board (folder empty) 1955 (Box 15)
  - Geology 1955 (Box 15)
  - Geography (folder empty) 1955 (Box 15)
  - Germanic Languages and Russian 1955 (Box 15)
  - Gifts and Grants 1955 (Box 15)
  - Governor's Office 1955 (Box 15)
  - Graduate School 1955 (Box 15)
  - "Ha-Hk" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 15)
  - "Ha-Hz" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 16)
  - Highway Department 1955 (Box 16)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1955 (Box 16)
  - History 1955 (Box 16)
  - Honors Courses (folder empty) 1955 (Box 16)
  - Honor System 1955 (Box 16)
  - Hospital (2 folders) 1955 (Box 16)
  - Hospital--Blue Cross (folder empty) 1955 (Box 16)
  - Hospital--Medical Board 1955 (Box 16)
  - Hospital--Monthly Statistical Reports 1955 (Box 16)
  - Hospital--Operating Budget 1955 (Box 16)
  - Housing 1955 (Box 17)
  - Hull Foundation (folder empty) 1955 (Box 17)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 17)
  - International Association of Universities (folder empty) 1955 (Box 17)
  - Institute of International Education 1955 (Box 17)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations (folder empty) 1955 (Box 17)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1955 (Box 17)
  - Insurance (folder empty) 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"A" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"B" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"C" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"D" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"E" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"F" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"G" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"H" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"I" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"J" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"K" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"L" 1955 (Box 17)
  - Invitations--"M" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"N" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"O" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"P" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"Q" (folder empty) 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"R" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"S" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"T" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"U" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"V" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"W" 1955 (Box 18)
  - Invitations--"X-Y-Z" 1955 (Box 18)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 19)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 19)
  - Jamestown Exposition 1955 (Box 19)
  - Japan Christian University 1955 (Box 19)
  - Jefferson--Miscellaneous (folder empty) 1955 (Box 19)
  - Jefferson--Memorial Foundation 1955 (Box 19)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 19)
  - Law School 1955 (Box 19)
  - Lectures--General 1955 (Box 19)
  - Lectures--Page-Barbour 1955 (Box 19)
  - Lectures--Richard 1955 (Box 19)
  - Lectures--William H. White Foundation 1955 (Box 19)
  - Legal Matters 1955 (Box 19)
  - Legislative Program 1955 (Box 20)
  - Library 1955 (Box 20)
  - Library--McGregor Library 1955 (Box 20)
  - Loan Funds (folder empty) 1955 (Box 20)
  - Lower Division 1955 (Box 20)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 20)
  - "Mi-Mz" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 20)
  - Madison Hall 1955 (Box 20)
  - Marine Corps 1955 (Box 20)
  - Mary Washington College--Alvey, Dean 1955 (Box 20)
  - Mary Washington College--Harris, Mrs. 1955 (Box 20)
  - Mary Washington College--Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 21)
  - Mary Washington College--Mr. Woodward 1955 (Box 21)
  - Mary Washington College--Music (Summer Course) 1955 (Box 21)
  - Mathematics 1955 (Box 22)
  - Medicine, School of 1955 (Box 22)
  - Military--Miscellaneous (folder empty) 1955 (Box 23)
  - Music 1955 (Box 23)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 23)
  - National Association of State Universities 1955 (Box 23)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1955 (Box 23)
  - National Education Association 1955 (Box 23)
  - National Science Foundation 1955 (Box 23)
  - Navy--General 1955 (Box 23)
  - Navy--ROTC 1955 (Box 23)
  - Nursing 1955 (Box 23)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 23)
  - Oak Ridge 1955 (Box 23)
  - "Pa-Pe" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 23)
  - "Pf-Pz" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 23)
  - Patents (folder empty) 1955 (Box 24)
  - Personnel (State) 1955 (Box 24)
  - Personnel and Placement Office 1955 (Box 24)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (folder empty) 1955 (Box 24)
  - Philosophy 1955 (Box 24)
  - Photographs 1955 (Box 24)
  - Physical Education (folder empty) 1955 (Box 24)
  - Physics 1955 (Box 24)
  - Political Science 1955 (Box 24)
  - Presidents' Council 1955 (Box 24)
  - Printing (folder empty) 1955 (Box 24)
  - Psychology 1955 (Box 24)
  - Public Occasions 1955 (Box 24)
  - Publication (folder empty) 1955 (Box 24)
  - Purchase and Printing (State Office) (folder empty) 1955 (Box 24)
  - Purchasing Office (University) 1955 (Box 24)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous (folder empty) 1955 (Box 24)
  - Questionnaires 1955 (Box 24)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 24)
  - Radio (folder empty) 1955 (Box 24)
  - Raven Society 1955 (Box 25)
  - Recommendations 1955 (Box 25)
  - Referendum 1955 (Box 25)
  - Regional Education 1955 (Box 25)
  - Registrar 1955 (Box 25)
  - Religion 1955 (Box 25)
  - Requisitions 1955 (Box 25)
  - Research--General 1955 (Box 25)
  - Research--Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1955 (Box 25)
  - Research--Bureau of Public Administration 1955 (Box 25)
  - Research--Institute for Research in the Social Sciences (folder empty) 1955 (Box 25)
  - Research--National Research Council (folder empty) 1955 (Box 25)
  - Research--President's Scientific Research Board (folder empty) 1955 (Box 25)
  - Richmond University Center 1955 (Box 25)
  - Rockefeller Foundation 1955 (Box 25)
  - Romance Languages 1955 (Box 25)
  - Rural Social Economics 1955 (Box 25)
  - "Sa-Sl" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 26)
  - "Sm-Sz" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 26)
  - Salaries 1955 (Box 26)
  - Segregation 1955 (Box 26)
  - Senate (University) 1955 (Box 26)
  - Sigma Xi (folder empty) 1955 (Box 26)
  - Social Security (folder empty) 1955 (Box 26)
  - Sociology 1955 (Box 26)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1955 (Box 26)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1955 (Box 26)
  - Southern Association of Science and Industry 1955 (Box 26)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (see Regional Education) (folder empty) 1955 (Box 26)
  - Southern University Conference 1955 (Box 26)
  - Speech and Drama 1955 (Box 26)
  - Speeches and Articles 1955 (Box 26)
  - State Board of Education 1955 (Box 26)
  - State Department of Health (folder empty) 1955 (Box 26)
  - State Universities Association 1955 (Box 26)
  - Statistics (folder empty) 1955 (Box 26)
  - Student Affairs Office--General 1955 (Box 27)
  - Student Aid Office 1955 (Box 27)
  - Student Health Department (folder empty) 1955 (Box 27)
  - Sullivan Award (folder empty) 1955 (Box 27)
  - Summer Session 1955 (Box 27)
  - Surplus Property 1955 (Box 27)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 27)
  - Television 1955 (Box 27)
  - Travel 1955 (Box 27)
  - Treasurer of Virginia 1955 (Box 27)
  - Treasury Department (U. S.) 1955 (Box 27)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 28)
  - United Nations 1955 (Box 28)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 28)
  - Veterans 1955 (Box 28)
  - Virginia Education Association 1955 (Box 28)
  - Virginia Institute for Scientific Research (folder empty) 1955 (Box 28)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1955 (Box 28)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1955 (Box 28)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council 1955 (Box 28)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Dockets and Minutes 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors (2 folders) 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Judge Barksdale 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Norborne Berkeley 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Black 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Coxe 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Ms. Dunn 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Dr. Emmett 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Gravatt 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Gray 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Hartfield 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Howard 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. McWane 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Mears 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Pollock 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mrs. Herbert M. Smith 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Howard Smith 1955 (Box 28)
  - Visitors--Mr. Talbott 1955 (Box 30)
  - Visitors--Ms. Wheeler 1955 (Box 30)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 30)
  - "Wi-Wz" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 30)
  - Women, Dean of 1955 (Box 30)
  - Wilson, Woodrow Birthplace Foundation 1955 (Box 30)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 30)